#### **PAKIZE BOZKURT**

Birmingham, B42 1NX

E: pakiozihak@gmail.com | M: 07309 234783

<u>linkedin.com/in/PakizeBozkurt</u> | <u>github.com/PakizeBozkurt</u>

https://react-portfolio-maai.onrender.com/

Bilingual graduate trainee in software development with a Master's Degree in Philosophy and +15 years' experience as a teacher and trainer. My strengths are problem solving, analytical skills, adaptability, public speaking, excellent communication, motivating others and getting things done. Genuine passion for software development and collaborating with other developers.

## **CAREER HISTORY**

# Software Developer, LangJo App (Team Project), UK

Mar 2023 - Sep 2023

Link: LangJo Repo

- Developed a MERN Stack project for English language learning in collaboration with a team of 3 more developers. Using an Agile workflow that created and closed 6 PRs and addressed 10 GitHub issues.
- Designed and Produced 8 React components, integrated 6 videos into MongoDB Atlas, and conducted testing using Thunder Client Extension in VSCode.

# Full Stack Developer, Study Buddies (Final project) at CYF, UK

May 2022 - Mar 2023

Link: Study-Buddies Repo

- Led the development of the Study Buddies app using JS, Node.js, and React within a tight deadline, which managed project repositories, tracked 4 milestones and conducted 15 code reviews.
- Collaborated with a team of 4 developers and a project manager to successfully deploy the app, which conducted user research, receiving an 85% user-friendliness rating.

## **GAP Period: Relocated & Adaptation to the UK**

Jan 2020 - May 2022

 Relocated to the UK in 2020 and dedicated time to learning English at James Watt College, alongside being involved in volunteer work to enhance my communication skills.

## **Group of Philosophy Teacher, Turkey**

Sep 2005 - Jan 2020

- Taught philosophy, psychology, sociology, logic, and democracy to high school students for 15 years.
- Managed philosophy classes, guiding over 600 students to achieve their academic goals.
- Organised 15 philosophy clubs and activities, encouraging over 200 students to engage in in-depth studies.
- Stayed updated with current developments in philosophy through professional development, attending over 20 seminars.

#### **EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS**

CodeYourFuture,, Full Stack Web Development-Program (Grade X) May 2022 - Apr 2023

Modules include:

Gazi University, MA in Philosophy, Turkey (Grade: 3.79) Sep 2013 – Jun 2016

Modules include:

Gazi University, BA Philosophy, Turkey (GPA: 2.98)

Modules include:

# **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

#### **Public Speaking Engagements**

- Tech Wednesday Event (International Women's Month), March 2023
- Delivered a motivational speech titled "Empowering Women in Tech: My Journey"
- Inspired 40 participants, encouraging them to pursue their passion for technology and overcome challenges.

# **Attending Panel**

- Code Your Future 'Women In Tech' Panel, April 2023
- Participated as the 2nd panellist, sharing valuable insights into my coding journey.
- Engaged in discussions about the challenges and opportunities for women in the tech industry.

## **COMMUNITY VOLUNTEERING**

British Heart Foundation 2021 to 2023
TeachingAssistant(CodeYourFuture) 2023
Digital helping 2023

# **SKILLS, INTERESTS & ACHIEVEMENTS**

## **Training and Skills:**

- Erasmus Project Training, Turkey, Nov 2019- Dec 2020
- Information Technologies Teacher Course, Fatih Project, Turkey, Oct 2012-Jan 2013
- Critical Thinking Strategies For Better Decisions ( NASBA)
- Conflict with Emotional Intelligence ( Udemy)
- Communicate Effectively at Work (Google)
- Problem Solving (Udemy)

**Coding:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node.js, MongoDB, TDD and PostgreSQL and some Devops experience

Languages: English (proficiency), Turkish (native)

Personal Interests: Reading, Knitting, Crochet, Volunteering, Recycling, Walking, Fresh Cooking